the list would contain major Urban
centers that up to this point had
escaped American firebombing as it was
hoped that their destruction would best
demonstrate the full extent of the
bomb's power the document also
stipulated that the target should be
located in a reasonably large urban area
it should lie on the Japanese main
Island area between Tokyo and Nagasaki
and that it should possess High
strategic value meeting all of these
criteria would be the city of Hiroshima
which would then be selected as the
first Target for a nuclear
attack located on the main Japanese
island of honu and home to nearly
340,000 people it was hoped that its
destruction would finally convince the
Japanese that they had no other choice
but to surrender with Hiroshima now
confirmed as the target a 9,000 atomic
bomb nicknamed little boy would be
transported to the Pacific where it
would arrive on the